

M

lamhrowena@gmail.com



(408) 714 - 9835



Elk Grove, CA



rowena.design



linkedin.com/in/lamhrowena



behance.net/rowenalam

# SKILLS

User Research

User Stories & Personas

Information Architecture

Wireframing & Prototyping

**Usability Testing** 

**Competitive Analysis** 

User Flows & Journey Maps

A/B Testing

Card Sorting

Basic HTML & CSS

Voice User Interface

# TOOLS

AdobeXD

Sketch

**InVision** 

Balsamiq

Marvel

Prott

Principle

Atom

GitHub

Alexa Developer Console

# Rowena Lam

# UI/UX Designer

A UI/UX Designer with a background in human development, education, customer service, gaming and payments. By combining my artistic abilities along with the skills I have acquired through my past, I am able to create fun and intuitive designs for user's experiences.

# **EDUCATION**

# UX Design CareerFoundry

01/2018 - 09/2020

- UX Fundamentals
- UI for UX Designers with InVision
- Voice User Interaction with Amazon Alexa
- UX Immersion
- Frontend Development for Designers

# Human Development, B.S. University of California, Davis

07/2007 - 03/2010

 Studied both the biological factors such as growth, physical maturation and aging, and social factors such as parenting, education and personal choices, that affect the developmental process of humans.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Payment Operations Associate**

HintMD (acquired by Revance Therapeutics, Inc)

02/2019 - Present

- Update policies and create high level documentation and flowcharts for payment operations process
- Collaborate with product and engineering team to discuss business requirements for PayFac MVP
- Analyze data from testing different KYC tools

# Online Risk Fraud Analyst

#### YapStone

08/2017 - 02/2019

- Conducted research to verify identity of payer or painted a story by forming connections between customer and cardholder.
- Communicated with merchants to advise them of best practices to prevent chargebacks, took note of their struggles with our process and shared feedback to upper management

# Fraud Risk Associate

#### **IMVU**

07/2015 - 08/2017

- Protected customers from account takeovers or identity theft and banning/disabling violators of TOS
- Worked on projects to analyze different fraud trends and reported results to take proper action
- Kept SOP and training documentation updated throughout all process and system changes for Fraud
  Team and provided guidelines to policy changes for Customer Service Team
- Collaborated with other teams to improve internal tools and ensure product and service excellence



# Rowena Lam UI/UX Designer

lamhrowena@gmail.com



(408) 714 - 9835



Elk Grove, CA



rowena.design

linkedin.com/in/lamhrowena

behance.net/rowenalam

# WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

### Customer Experience, Lead Corsair

#### 05/2015 - 07/2015

- Compiled reports weekly for live support stats, RMA/refunds, sales operations, Webstore fraud and shipping delays, and presented data to CEO, COO, CIO, Sr. Directors and E-commerce Managers
- Created process documentation and planned & executed 2-week training program with 13 new staff in Customer Service and Webstore duties
- Conducted interviews when hiring new customer service agents

# Customer Service Representative & Webstore Lead

### Corsair

06/2014 - 05/2015

- Communicated with customers via phone, email/tickets and live chat to answer Webstore inquiries, resolve issues with products and process RMA's
- Collaborated with Product & Channel Marketing teams to manage backlog and fulfill orders in a timely manner
- Worked daily with shipping team to correct inbound/outbound discrepancies and finance team to forward sensitive bank information to issue ACH/wire transfer refunds

# Play Movies Operations Specialist

### Google (contract via oDesk)

09/2013 - 11/2013

- Compared top films with competitor's market and notified YouTube team of missing films in Play Store
- Compiled weekly reports for the Engineering team to calculate financial impact
- Linked movie titles to upkeep our internal knowledge base

# **Android Applications Team Lead**

### Google (contract via Randstad)

02/2013 - 06/2013

- Manually reviewed Android mobile apps for quality assurance to meet tablet optimization criteria while providing data for the engineering team to build an automated system & the Play Store's "Designed for Tablets" list.
- Supported developers in the appeals process to optimize their UI to be used on 7" and 10" tablets.
- Analyzed the quality of reviews from colleagues and record decision reversals to calculate error percentages and updated productivity logs daily to send end-of-week reports to Operations Manager
- Trained new app testers in policy and procedures and acted as a point of contact for technical and quality subject matters

# Tier 2 Hardware Call Center Agent

# Google (contract via Randstad)

#### 12/2012 - 02/2013

- Informed consumers of features of Nexus devices and Chromebooks
- Troubleshot issues via email and phone regarding devices, shipping, tax exemptions, warranties and Google Play accounts
- Resolved Tier 1 agent consults to meet customer expectations and effectively escalated issues to Tier 3 agents with clear communication.